Dmitry Snisarenko Frontend Developer

Last update: Wed Aug 01 2018 08:20:55 GMT+0200 (CEST)

The online version is available at https://sneas.github.io/cv

Biography

Residence

Weesp, Dichtershof, NL

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-s-74a4b830/

Email

snisarenkodima@gmail.com

Languages

English, Russian, and a little bit of Dutch

Why I'm doing this

My goals and ambitions are to free up people from meaningless recurring work and help them to achieve their objectives with a minimal effort.

How I'm doing this

For users

By providing smooth user experience concerning physiology, psychology and data integrity principles

For developers

By automating development process with the help of continuous integration and continuous deployment systems

For developers

By helping to develop reasonable and flexible component-based architecture

For testers

By automating testing routines and including them into release cycle

For designers

By establishing and maintaining design systems and frontend component libraries

For the team

By initiating collaboration between team members and stakeholders on improving scrum/agile process within organisation

For myself

By challenging my own limitations and weaknesses

Career insights

Excited about computer programming, automation, typography, and design since 1996.

Visual and animation designer for the local TV channel between 2000 and 2003.

Started professional career as a fullstack LAMP developer in 2005.

Remote freelancer between 2010 and 2014. I received extremely positive feedback from all of my clients. You can read it here

(https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/_~01752134695731685e/).

Pure frontender since 2012.

Employment

KLM Royal Dutch Airlines

Senior frontend developer

Feb 2017 - present

Project: Real time mobile application used by KLM mechanics in Schiphol airport.

Angular 5 [Ionic 3] [Redux] [RxJS] [Typescript] [SASS] [Webpack 2] [Karma]

Knab hypotheken

Senior frontend developer

Jun 2014 - Feb 2017

Project: Registration flow, mortgage tools

Responsibilities: Maintain existing project and provide new tools and components.

Main achievements: Backbone -> Angular 1.3 transition. Introduction of TDD with Karma and E2E with Protractor. Angular 1.3 -> Angular 1.5 transition. Introduction of component library.

AngularJS (Karma) (Protractor) (SASS) (Gulp) (Bootstrap) (Heroku

upwork.com

Senior frontend developer

Oct 2012 - Jun 2014

A high traffic website. The biggest player on freelance job market.

Responsibilities: Maintain existing application, developed new features and components.

Main achievements: Introduction of TDD process with PHPUnit and qUnit. Job post template engine.

```
Javascript (jQuery) (qUnit) (GruntJS) (Selenium) (Compass/SASS) (PHP)
```

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering. Sevastopol State Technical University [2002 – 2007]

Certification

- Professional Scrum Master I Apr 2, 2018
- React Nanodegree Dec 27, 2017
 Projects accomplished:
 - ots accomplished.
 - https://github.com/sneas/myreads (React)
 - https://github.com/sneas/readable React Redux
 - https://github.com/sneas/mobile-flashcards (React Native) (Redux)
- Zend Certified Engineer (PHP 5.3) Jan 24, 2011

Additional experience

A complete list of side/hobby projects: https://github.com/sneas.

Some cool projects:

Component Library

https://github.com/sneas/component-library

The easiest way to create HTML component library for existing website.

ES6 NodeJS SASS

A solution to CORS problem of Ionic and WKWebView

https://github.com/sneas/ionic-native-http-connection-backend

This project's become quite popular since Ionic made WKWebView a default web container.

Namespaced Bootstrap

https://github.com/sneas/bootstrap-sass-namespace

Non-conflicting bootstrap integration. Consider using this project if Bootstrap has to be applied partially. ie to particular div of a page.

